翻译：饿得慌  zhanginfo  肉松  幸田实果子
翻译：丁小七  川川  葉子  慕秋雪
校对：wdjmhs  zhanginfo  慕秋雪    时间轴：紫熏   凭陵新月
后期：饿得慌    监制：wdjmhs
国土安全
第三季 第十一集
美国空军及海军
Air and naval forces of the United States
对恐怖组织发起了一系列攻击
launched a series of strikes against terrorist facilities...
泛美航空103号班机于洛克比失事
Pan Am flight 103 crashed into the town of Lockerbie.
他已批准在非洲  欧洲和中东的恐怖行动
He has sanctioned acts of terror in Africa, Europe, the Middle East.
我们不容科威特遭受侵略
This will not stand, this aggression against Kuwait.
对于恐怖袭击的不懈打击
This relentless pursuit of terror.
我们将一视同仁
We will make no distinction...
美国军舰科尔号
The USS Cole was attacked
在亚丁湾港口加油时遭到袭击
while refueling in the port of Aden.
这是恐怖主义行动
This was an act of terrorism.
这是可鄙懦弱的行动
It was a despicable and cowardly act.
下面为您演奏的
The next samba we're going to swing for you
是一首经典曲目
is one of the good old favorites.
直到他受到了阻击
...until something stops him.
整个事件就发生在我的眼前
It was right in front of my eyes,
而我丝毫没预料到
and I never saw it coming.
该飞机撞向了世贸中心
That plane crashed into the World Trade Center.
成千上万的民众东奔西逃
Thousands of people running.
我们必须  也将在国内外保持警惕
We must and we will remain vigilant at home and abroad.
你是我见过最聪明
You're the smartest and the dumbest fucking person
又最愚蠢的人
I've ever known.
我不是不明真相的那个人
I'm not the one who got it wrong.
我是唯一的明白人
I'm the only one who got it right.
拿下
Take 'em.
通通拿下
Take 'em all.
《国土安全》前情提要
Previously on Homeland:
索尔  我以为你今晚不回来了
Saul, I didn't expect you back tonight.
这位是阿伦·伯纳德
This is Alain Bernard.
阿伦·伯纳德承认自己是以色列情报人员
Alain Bernard admitted to being an asset of Israeli intelligence.
把他丢进地洞里关着去
Put him in a dark fucking hole.
现在我们来说说纳赛尔·赫佳兹
It's time we talk about Nasser Hejazi,
你用这个名字从革命卫队中挪用了4500万美元
whose name you used to embezzle more than $45 million.
你现在成了自己国家的敌人
You are now an enemy of your own state.
我已经为你计划好了
I got plans for you.
什么计划
What plans?
我要把你放回伊朗
I'm gonna play you back into Iran.
从现在起  你为我们做事
From now on, you work for us.
我设了个局
I have a play.
牵涉到了布洛迪
It involves Brody.
你有什么好主意
What's your big idea?
达尼什·阿克巴里
Danesh Akbari.
伊朗革命卫队的首领
Head of Iran's Revolutionary Guard.
对
Right.
贾瓦迪的上司
Javadi's boss.
布洛迪能接触到他
Brody can get to him.
他们送我至边境处
The guys get me to the border
然后我示意投降
where I surrender myself?
没错
Correct.
发生了什么事
What just happen?
火力太猛了
We are under heavy fire!
撤退  撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
我不撤退
I'm not going back.
这件事你一个人做不到
You can't do this by yourself.
我距离边界不到三百米了  卡莉
I'm 300 yards from the border, Carrie!
我能完成任务
I can make it!
你会死在那里的
You will die over there!
不  你错了  卡莉
No, you're wrong, Carrie!
因为你会来带我回去
'Cause you're gonna get me home!
不  不准那么说
No, don't say that!
不要把压力强加给我  那简直是白日梦
Do not put that on me! It's a fantasy!
你会想出办法的  我对你有信心
You'll find a way. I have faith.
我是尼古拉斯·布洛迪
...Nicholas Brody.
我因为中情局爆炸事件被美国通缉
[波斯语]
布洛迪成功越境了
Brody made it across.
你呢  索尔
And you, Saul,
还依旧身在局中
are still in the game.
我会下地狱的
I'll be damned.
你在德黑兰有个叔叔
You have an uncle in Tehran.
-让我们俩单独待一会  -是  长官
- Give us a few minutes. - Yes, sir.
他们每天让我放一小时的风
They let me out one hour a day.
锻炼身体
To exercise.
那个房间就比这里大一丁点
In a room that's... three feet bigger than this.
你窃取我们的情报  就只能受这种待遇
Well, you spy on us, that's what you get.
我不是间谍
I'm not a spy.
我们当场抓获了你
Well, we caught you red-handed.
你是抓到我跟你老婆偷情
You caught me with your wife.
你最好别跟我对着干
You don't want to be antagonizing me,
毕竟我是来放你出去的
not when I'm here to get you out.
你想让我干什么
What do you want?
我有项任务正在实施
I have an operation in progress.
在德黑兰
In Tehran.
那项任务的支援队伍已被迫撤离
Support team for that operation was forced to pull out.
摩萨德在当地安插有特工
Mossad has agents on the ground there.
我需要两名特工
I need two of them.
你可以自己问特拉维夫要
You can ask Tel Aviv yourself.
他们会问许多有关任务的问题
Well, they'd ask a lot of questions about the mission,
我没准备好要回答
questions I'm not prepared to answer.
-但就算我找人也没什么区别  -最好有区别
- But it won't be any different if I ask. - It better be.
因为我现在跟你这个干了我老婆的滑头啰嗦
'Cause it's the only reason I'm standing here talking
就是为了让你办成这件事
to the greaseball who fucked my wife.
没人希望让你待在这里
No one wants you here.
摩萨德不想  我也不想
Not Mossad, not me.
彼此帮个忙
Do everyone a favor.
把事做成
Make this happen.
阿布·纳齐尔生前帮我安排了逃跑路线
Abu Nazir arranged my escape route for me.
我从哈利法克斯藏进一艘货船的集装箱
I left Halifax in a container on a freighter.
去了哥伦比亚
It took me to Columbia.
又被辆吉普车拉到委内瑞拉
There I was taken by Jeep to Venezuela.
过境时出了些麻烦
There was trouble at the border.
-所以遭到了枪击  -谁开的枪
- That's when I was shot. - By?
不知道  想领赏的人吧
I don't know. Someone trying to collect the reward.
然后呢
And then?
都告你了
I told you.
他们
They...
他们把我弄到了加拉加斯
they took me to Caracas.
那栋烂尾楼
To this... slum.
你就是在那里变成瘾君子的
Where you became an addict.
什么  不  不是
What? Wait. No. No.
我中了枪
I was shot.
这里  还有这里
Here and here.
他们用海洛因给我止痛
They used heroin on me for the pain.
是很难戒  但我戒了
It wasn't easy to stop, but I did.
-用了多久  -没多久
- How long did that take? - A while.
-有艾滋吗  -没有
- Do you have AIDS? - No.
检查过吗
Have you been tested?
咱们扯这些干嘛
Why are we even talking about this?
我没艾滋
I don't have AIDS.
我离开加拉加斯是不想死在那里
I left Caracas because I was gonna die there.
有个伊玛目帮我逃出来的
An Imam helped me get out,
到了伊朗这里  我就是想避难
get here to Iran, and I just want asylum.
真不理解你们干嘛这么折磨我
I don't understand why you're giving me such a hard time.
你觉得这就是我们要做的事情吗
Is that what you think we're doing?
就是为了折磨你吗
Giving you a hard time?
我已经
I've...
赶了这么远的路
I've traveled so far,
还险些死在路上  我是想
and I almost didn't make it, and I just thought...
到了这边就安全了  还以为
I just thought I'd be safe here. I just...
能受到些礼遇
I just thought I'd be welcome.
凭什么
Why?
凭我做的事
Because of what I did.
端了中情局
Bombed Langley.
他们的核心啊
Their heart.
你想什么呢
You think what?
我们会欢迎叛国者吗
We like traitors here?
不是
No.
-谁派你来的  -没人  都告诉你了
- Who sent you? - No one. I told you.
我就是想避难
I just want asylum.
就是想...想歇歇
I just w... want rest.
要休息一下吗
Should we take a break?
太好了  拜托
Yes. Please. Please.
不行
No.
再过一遍
Go over it again.
女士专用的士  叫车专线:1821
[法语]
谢谢
Merci.
[法语]
-你好  -你好
- Bonjour. - Bonjour.
[法语]
女士
Madame?
您收好
Voilà
谢谢
Merci.
谢谢您  女士
Merci pour vous, madame.
他们要您上去
可以等等吗  十分钟后我有个会
阿克巴里将军找您呢  先生
[阿拉伯语]
马苏德·施拉吉
Masud Sherazi?
你是
Yes?
我是你侄女的朋友
I'm a friend of your niece.
你有东西要交给我吧
You have something for me.
东西呢
Where is it?
先说说是怎么回事
First you tell me what's going on.
法拉怎么和你说的
What did Fara say to you?
她要我帮个忙
That she needed a favor.
出于对你的保护  你知道这些就可以了
For your own protection, that's all you want to know.
这也算是保护我吗
And was this for my protection?
从海关走私违禁物  还送到我家里
Sending contraband through customs, here to my house?
-东西没走海关  -上面写着呢
- It never went through customs. - It says!
不是  那是我们的标签
No, those are our labels.
从日内瓦发的外交包裹
It came by diplomatic pouch from Geneva.
你是中情局的吧
You're CIA, aren't you?
我是你侄女的朋友
I'm a friend of your niece's.
那她也是中情局的了
So she's CIA, too.
为她祖国的敌对国工作
Working against her own country.
是为她的祖国工作
Working for her country.
她相信你理解这点
She trusted you to underand that.
她让我把这个给你
She asked me to give you this.
她在美国也戴头巾吗
She wears the hijab there in America?
我觉得她的心还在这里
I think her heart is here still,
还在德黑兰
in Tehran.
那我的兄弟
And my brother,
他同意她这么做吗
does he approve what she's doing?
我认为他逐渐接受了
My understanding is he's grown to accept it.
谢谢
Thank you.
告诉我  你还需要什么
Tell me, is there anything else you need?
你相信他只是来避难的吗
我们仍在核查他那番话
那你相信他吗
不确定
有人出现在边境  我们得多加小心
你对他太温和了
我知道
如果你真有疑虑...
我觉得他在这是客  是贵宾
可能有巨大的宣传价值
这个炸了中情局的人吗
他是炸了中情局的美国士兵
过去式的美国"英雄"
他这辈子算是受尽磨难了
我觉得不该再折磨他了
我们得确认可以相信他
然后才能让全世界知道他在这
是的  长官
[波斯语]
我提个建议如何
也许你该和布洛迪面谈  由您亲自判断
这是要事  值得考虑
-拿到手机了吗  -是
- You got the phone? - Yeah.
她叔叔怎么样
How was the uncle?
开始有疑虑  后来没事了
He was dodgy at first, then okay.
你那边情况如何
How did you make out?
阿伦说通了摩萨德的人
Alain got Mossad to say yes.
很好
Good.
给你安排了两名特工准备见你
I have two agents on the ground there ready to meet you.
都是伊朗籍的
Both Iranian nationals.
他们知道多少
What do they know?
我尽可能少告诉他们
I told everyone as little as possible.
你来决定告诉他们多少
You need to decide how much to let them in.
我跟他们说了
I did tell them
他们参与的是近距离暗杀行动
they'll be supporting a close-quarters assassination,
你需要一把武器
and that you'll be needing a weapon.
希望第一次见面他们能有些方案
Expect them to bring some options to the first meeting.
我想把见面安排在法拉叔叔家
I'd like to make it at the uncle's house.
你确定吗
You sure?
确定
Yeah.
那里很安全  我相信他
It's safe there. I trust him.
现在你宾馆有卫星监控
I got a satellite over your hotel right now.
我在七楼阳台上
I'm on the balcony-- seventh floor.
你是不是包着头巾
Is that a head scarf you're wearing?
你开玩笑的  是吧
You're kidding, right?
看得见个鬼
I can't see crap.
太暗了
It's too dark.
贾瓦迪那还没什么消息
We haven't heard much from Javadi,
应该算是件好事
but we're taking that as a good thing.
他们把布洛迪藏在阿扎迪塔附近了
They got Brody stashed at a compound near Azadi Tower.
显然他在努力撑着
Apparently, he's holding together.
还不错
Well enough anyway.
熬过了整整三天的审讯
He survived three solid days of interrogations.
卡莉
Carrie?
怎么了
What?
你还好吗
You good?
我该挂了
Uh, I should probably go.
明天...明天是个大日子
It's a... it's a big day tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
我们不能接受这样
We didn't agree to this.
我只知道有两名情报人员准备就绪
Yeah, well, I was told we had two assets ready to go.
没有姓名  没有地点
No names, no places.
时机成熟你们会知道的
You will learn when you need to.
我现在就得知道
I need to know now.
不  我现在就得知道能相信你们
No, I need to know now that I can trust you.
而目前为止  你们说的话不能让我相信
And so far, nothing you've said is making me think that.
我们要求摩萨德派两个好手
We asked Mossad for the two best men in Iran.
结果是你们二位
They sent you and you.
他们错了吗
Were they wrong?
你需要帮助的暗杀行动  在哪
This assassination you need help-- where?
我还不清楚
I don't know yet.
什么时候
When?
我也不确定  但很快
I'm not sure, but soon.
我们不是这么办事的  什么都等着看情况
This is not how we work-- everything wait and see.
我跟你们说
I will tell you this.
行动目标是伊朗革命卫队领袖
The target is the head of the IRGC.
达尼什·阿克巴里吗
Danesh Akbari?
没人能接近他
No one can get close to him.
我们能
We can.
他会被就地待命的美国人拿下
He'll be taken down by an American already in place.
我们的工作就是让他全身而退
Our job is to get that man to safety afterwards.
你们能做到吗
Can you do that?
他们说不能用枪
They say no gun.
这是氰化物
Is cyanide.
这个  美国人
This, uh, American--
他需要近身阿克巴里
he will need to be right next to Akbari.
而阿克巴里肯定有保镖护卫
And Akbari will be guarded.
是的  他有贴身卫队
Yes. He travels with a full security detail.
[波斯语]
我们有C-4炸药
We have C-4.
我们可以声东击西
We can create a diversion.
但这个怎么办
But what about this?
谁去交给那个美国人
Who will get this to the American?
我来处理
I'll take care of it.
巴吉鲁女士吗
Madame Bezieux?
我是  怎么了
那些人在打听你
我看就是例行公事
有什么事吗
这边请
This way, please.
我们要去哪儿
你们要带我去哪儿
我没做错事
我是贵国游客  有权利知道
安静  安静
Quiet! Quiet!
我还是喜欢你金发碧眼的样子
I liked you better as a blonde.
有必要吗
Was this really necessary?
你想怎样  在大堂里喝酒吗
What do you want, drinks in the lobby?
你让那个前台怀疑我了
You've got the desk clerk wondering about me now.
你记住  我根本不想让你来
Remember, I didn't want you here at all.
任务是阿克巴里
The mission is Akbari.
那才是任务
That's the mission.
你来这儿干嘛  帮布洛迪脱逃
What you're here for, getting Brody out--
大可不必
strictly optional.
可以了吗
Are we agreed?
任务是阿克巴里  没错
The mission is Akbari, yes.
好的
Good.
好
有事发生了
Something happened.
怎么了
What?
阿克巴里白天从不离开办公室
Akbari never leaves his office during the day.
他说太危险
Too risky, he says.
但他明天要了一支安全车队
But he's requested a secure convoy for tomorrow.
-他要出门  -去哪儿
- He's heading out. - Where?
没人会说
No one's saying.
但我昨天告诉他
But I told him yesterday
应该和布洛迪亲自谈谈
that he should really talk to Brody in person.
要开始了
So, it's on?
就用这个吗
Is that it? The device?
是的
Yeah.
以色列的货
Israeli.
能交给布洛迪吗
Can you get it to Brody?
我会想办法的
I'll find a way.
好了  都听好
Okay, listen up.
我们在德黑兰有行动
We have movement in Tehran.
无论如何  我们都希望
We now expect closure on our operation,
这项任务
one way or another
能在当地时间明早9点左右结束
at approximately 9:00 A.M. tomorrow local time.
情报人员认为此次行动会在
Intelligence suggests this will take place
布洛迪被羁押的阿扎迪塔
at a compound near Azadi Tower
附近某建筑进行
where Brody is currently held.
武器  氰化物针
The weapon, a cyanide needle,
正在转交给他
is being delivered to him,
还有他的撤离计划
along with the plan for his extraction.
布洛迪的任务是
Brody's job is to position himself
直接和目标达尼什·阿克巴里碰面
in direct contact with the target, Danesh Akbari.
-他怎么通过守卫  -不用
- How does he get past the guards? - He doesn't.
目标来见他
Target comes to him.
最好能私下里会见
We're expecting a personal encounter,
由阿克巴里提出
initiated by Akbari.
我们有两名摩萨德特工待命
We have two Mossad agents in place,
一个从这栋楼
one with a direct sightline
直接监视楼宇情况
into the compound from this building here.
另一名特工会在布洛迪接近阿克巴里后
That agent will remotely detonate a motorcycle bomb
至少也要在两人共处一室时
in this alley at a moment
在这条路上
when Brody is proximal to Akbari,
远程引爆摩托车上的炸弹
at the very least in the same room.
爆炸会造成混乱
The explosion should generate sufficient confusion
使布洛迪干掉目标
to allow Brody to take out the target
并从房子的后门逃走
and escape through this doorway at the rear of the compound.
这里可以直接通向街道
It provides a clear exit to the street
我们的两名特工会在车里等他
where our two agents will be waiting in a vehicle.
如果计划顺利  布洛迪会在几小时后
If the rest follows plan, Brody will be delivered
被转送到德黑兰外的一所安全屋
to a safe house outside Tehran a few hours later.
有意见吗
Comments?
我明白  不确定因素还很多
I'm aware-- it's a lot of moving parts.
此次行动卡莉什么角色
Where's Carrie in all this?
她的工作已经完成
She's done her job
整合逃亡计划
putting together an extraction plan.
行动前不应该让她撤离吗
Shouldn't she be pulled out before the event?
她不这么看
She doesn't see it that way.
好了
Okay.
准备吧
Let's get ready.
还剩不到12小时
We have less than 12 hours.
起来  快
Get up. Now!
怎么了
What's going on?
起来把衣服穿上  快点
Get up and get dressed... quickly!
为什么  怎么了
Why? What's happening?
穿这个  快点
In these. Hurry.
我的鞋呢
Where are my shoes?
鞋
Shoes.
给你鞋  快点
Shoes. Hurry.
我觉得他们要出发了
I think they're moving.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他们要带他走
They are taking him somewhere.
[波斯语]
该死的  你先回来
Shit. Get back here.
索尔  你在看吗
Saul, are you seeing this?
布洛迪被带走了
Brody's being moved.
我们看到了
We see it.
他们是带他去阿克巴里那里吗
Are they taking him to Akbari?
不  阿克巴里的保镖队
No. Akbari's convoy
六分钟前就离开了伊革命卫队
left the IRGC six minutes ago.
我们还以为是去你那里
We thought he was coming to you.
所以布洛迪他妈的是要去哪里
So where the fuck is Brody going?
我们得跟上他们
Hey, we need to follow them.
你们派的刺客居然是尼古拉斯·布洛迪
Your assassin is Nicholas Brody?
对  我们能开始行动了吗
Yes. Can we get moving?
他可是世界头号通缉犯
The most wanted man in the world.
这么重要的事居然不告诉我们
This was not important for us to know?
那现在你知道了
Well, now you know.
我们走吧
Let's go.
快走吧
注意这里
Look at this.
阿克巴里和布洛迪的车队正在靠拢
Akbari. Brody. The convoys are converging.
朝哪里靠拢
Converging where?
一个叫达瓦吉噶尔的地方
An area called Darvazy Gar.
阿克巴里的车停下了
Akbari's stopping.
他的人封锁了那个地方
His men are locking down the area.
他们在罗斯塔米街
They're on Rostami Street.
卡莉在哪里
Where's Carrie?
布洛迪后面两个街区
Two blocks behind Brody.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
马上就到了
Almost there.
阿克巴里进了那栋楼
Akbari's gone inside that house.
查出住户的身份
Find out who lives there.
我们正在查
Yeah. We're looking.
别忙着找  问一下贾瓦迪
Don't just look. Ask Javadi.
地址是罗斯塔米街421号
The address is 421 Rostami Street.
卡莉
Carrie,
阿克巴里和布洛迪在你前方90米处
Akbari and Brody are 100 yards ahead of you.
会面开始了
Meeting is on.
在这里停
Stop here.
停  快停下
Stop! Stop.
这不是个好主意  我们毫无准备
This is not a good idea. We are not set up.
我们有准备  布洛迪见到了阿克巴里
We are. Brody's meeting Akbari.
唯一有变化的是地点
The only thing that's changed is the location.
布洛迪知道我们在这里吗
Does Brody even know we are here?
他听到爆炸声就会知道了
As soon as he hears the explosion, he'll know.
优素福现在需要找个地方
Yousef needs to find a place now.
我们现在最好暂时收手
The best thing is for us to back away,
等待一个更好的机会
wait for a better chance.
不会再有更好的机会了  你搞清楚这点
There won't be a better chance, do you understand?
只管照做
Just do it.
优素福
Yousef...
[波斯语]
牵制炸弹装好了
Diversion is set.
卡莉  你来指挥
Your call, Carrie.
你有现场指挥的便利
You're the eyes on the ground.
优素福
Yousef...
[波斯语]
这操他娘的发生了什么事
The fuck what is happening?
阿克巴里离开了
Akbari's leaving.
他们根本没有碰面  阿克巴里走了
They never met. Akbari's gone.
我想他是要进那栋楼里去
I think he's going inside the house.
我他妈的最后问一遍
For the last fucking time,
我们能不能查到是谁住在那里
can we find out who lives there?
[波斯语]
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
索尔  贾瓦迪的消息
Saul, a message from Javadi:
罗斯塔米街421号属于伊革命卫队
421 Rostami is owned by the IRGC.
现在的住户叫纳塞林·莫勒彼
Current resident... Nassrin Mughrabi.
卡莉  布洛迪见的是纳塞林·莫勒彼
Carrie, Brody is meeting with Nassrin Mughrabi.
纳塞林  那是谁
Nassrin? Who is that?
阿布·纳齐尔的遗孀
Abu Nazir's widow.
阿克巴里为什么要这么做
Why did Akbari do this?
布洛迪曾在纳塞林家住过两年
Brody lived in Nassrin's house for two years.
阿克巴里用她来审查布洛迪
Akbari's using her to vet Brody.
阿克巴里告诉我你在这里的时候
When Akbari told me you were here,
我根本不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
但是你还是出现了
But here you are.
我的尼古拉斯
My Nicholas.
我完全没想到你会住在德黑兰
I had no idea you were living in Tehran.
纳齐尔死后我一直住这里
It's been my home since Nazir died.
我很抱歉  纳塞林
I'm sorry, Nassrin.
再没有人能像他一样了
There was no one like him.
再也没有了
No one.
看得出来你经历了很多
But I can see you have been through a lot.
我上次见你的时候
When I last saw you,
你像个就要上战场的士兵
you were like a soldier going to war.
我现在是从战场归来的士兵
Now I'm a soldier back from war.
得胜归来
With a victory.
根本算不上什么胜利
It's hard to see it like that.
我失去了那么多
I lost so much.
你的家人
Your family.
尤其是我的女儿
My daughter, especially.
当我...
When I, um...
当我完成任务
when I completed the... the plan that, um,
安拉交付我的使命
Allah had set out for me...
这击垮了她
it destroyed her.
她试图自杀
She tried to kill herself.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
信念的缺失让人迷茫
It is hard when you don't have faith.
她有信念
She had faith.
她相信她的父亲不会背叛她
She had faith that her own father wouldn't betray her
让她生不如死
and make her life unlivable.
纳齐尔帮你做好了思想准备
Nazir prepared you for this.
他说只要你忠于安拉
He said that if you were true to Allah,
你会心如止水
you would find peace.
你是虔诚的
And you were true.
你也是
And so were you.
你心如止水了吗
Have you found peace?
有时能
Sometimes... yes.
但有时我会问
But sometimes I ask
为什么真主要带走我的儿子
why God had to take my son
和丈夫  而留下我
and my husband instead of me,
然后我的感觉和你女儿一样
and then I feel like your daughter did:
生不如死
life is unlivable.
但我挺过来了
But I survive.
我们都应该这样
It's what we do.
对
Yes.
我们挣脱苦海
We crawl out of the rubble
重新振作
and we gather up the bodies.
你为什么来德黑兰  尼古拉斯
Why did you come to Tehran, Nicholas?
我无处可去
I had nowhere else.
你来这里干什么
What do you want here?
我想结束逃亡
I want to stop running.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
[波斯语]
告诉我们你在这里干什么
Tell us what you are doing here.
你在这里干什么
What... what are you doing here?
蒙主恩泽
By the grace of God...
我来这里寻求庇护
I am here to seek asylum.
只有在这里  我才能心如止水
This is the only place in the world that I can find peace.
你是德黑兰的名人了  布洛迪
You're a big man in Tehran, Brody.
真正的大人物
A really big man now.
六天后
在你那段著名的录像里  你说
In your famous videotape, you said,
我爱我的祖国
"I love my country."
我是真心的
Which I meant.
但美国却把你列为国家公敌
And yet America declares you an enemy of the state.
美国人的自我标榜与现实的美国
There's a wide gulf between what America says it is
是天壤之别
and what it actually is.
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
最新的羞辱
The most recent insult.
这是否能解释你12月12日的行动
Does this explain your actions on December 12?
是的
It does.
对
Yes.
[波斯语]
布洛迪在一周内学了波斯语
Brody learned enough Farsi in one week
为了在国家电视节目中谴责我们
to denounce us on state television.
标准的"美国去死"论调
Standard "Death to America" fare.
[波斯语]
但我听说他的移送过程很顺利
But I'm told his delivery is pitch-perfect.
刚刚和他通过电话
Just got off the phone with him.
他要求"行动"
He demanded "Action."
没错
Yeah.
我接到了相同的电话
I got the same call.
布洛迪这部分行动
The Brody part of the operation
总是很艰难  索尔
was always a long shot, Saul.
所有部分都很难
It was all a long shot.
行动奏效了
And it worked,
在此之前
until now.
布洛迪不可能接近阿克巴里
Brody's never going to get anywhere near Akbari.
我知道
I know.
贾瓦迪的直接消息
That's straight from Javadi.
布洛迪已经被伊朗公关部接手
Brody's been handed off to their PR department.
我们没有机会了
Our window is closed.
那我们要放弃他吗
So we just discard him?
我们想让他撤离
We tried to extract him.
但布洛迪没有在集合点露面
Brody didn't even show up for the rendezvous.
现在他在整个德黑兰大放厥词
Now he's spouting off all over Tehran.
最起码
Bottom line,
布洛迪从线人变成了大累赘
Brody's gone from asset to serious liability.
我得知道他怎么想的
I need to know what he's thinking.
他的想法显而易见
It's obvious what he's thinking:
就是他在那些网络视频中说的话
what he's saying on all those YouTube videos.
伊朗救了他
Iran saved his life,
他热爱伊朗  憎恨美国
he loves them, hates us.
你知道还有什么吗
And you know what else?
无论他现在脑子里想些什么
Whatever he's thinking today,
谁能确保在今后不会变成现实
who's to say what it will be tomorrow?
他和当初将他洗脑的同一拨人
He's spending his days with the same people
生活在一起
who brainwashed him in the first place,
对于布洛迪可以确认的一点
and one thing we know about Brody is
就是这个家伙反复无常
this is a guy who changes his mind.
你在伊革命卫队中安插了重要线人
You placed a major asset inside the IRGC.
马吉德·贾瓦迪
Majid Javadi.
这是值得我们继续利用的重大胜利
That's a huge victory worth preserving.
布洛迪随时会暴露贾瓦迪的身份
Brody could expose him at any moment,
事情很简单
and the simple fact is
我们不能信任布洛迪
we can't trust Brody.
不能信任
We never could.
该结束了
We need to end it.
你是说杀了布洛迪吗
You mean end Brody?
总统希望能解决此问题
The president wants this resolved.
我们知道布洛迪每日做祷告的地方
We know where Brody prays every day.
摩萨德在那边也有人
Mossad has some men on the ground there.
是时候了
It's time.
他当然要抨击我们
Of course he's bad-mouthing us.
你指望他说什么
What do you expect?
只有这样  他才能不被怀疑  索尔
He's doing what he needs to, to preserve his cover, Saul.
仅此而已
That's all.
冷静下  我只是问问
Well, calm down. I'm just asking.
计划有变
The plan changed,
按照我们通常的做法
so we do what we always do,
我们随机应变
what he's doing-- we adjust.
我们应变过了
We did adjust.
我们试图让他撤走
We tried lifting him out of there.
他没理会
He blew us off.
那是因为他觉得原计划能成功
Because he still thinks the plan can work.
这是他的原话吗
Is that what he's saying?
这是我的话
That's what I'm saying.
所以  他还没和你联系吗
So he hasn't reached out to you?
没有  我们一直都说  和我联系
No. We said all along any contact with me
风险太大  不是吗
was too risky, right?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
你是时候该回来了
It's time you got on a plane and came back.
我们不能就这么把他丢在这里
We can't just abandon him here.
索尔  从始至终我对他的判断都是正确的
Saul, I have been right about him this whole time.
我知道
I know.
等你回来了  我们再好好谈
And we'll talk it through when you're back.
卡莉
Carrie?
卡莉  听得到吗
Carrie, you hear me?
听得到
Yeah, sure.
再见
Bye.
拜
她才不会乖乖地坐上飞机
She's not getting on any plane.
我知道
I know.
我们来解决吧
Let's get it done.
现在就去
Do it now.
马苏德  我是卡莉
Masud. It's Carrie.
你得再帮我一次
I need one more favor.
日安
Salaam.
[波斯语]
有个朋友待会儿会给你打电话
A friend will call you now.
[波斯语]
请你在里面等我一会儿
Will you wait inside for me a moment, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Yes?
是我  我就站在庭院对面
It's me. I'm across the courtyard.
布洛迪  我有车
Brody, I have a car.
我得把你带离德黑兰
I need to get you out of Tehran.
我跟他们说过了  我不走
I told them already, I don't want to leave.
我知道  你的话让他们觉得不安
I know, and it made them nervous.
不安  这什么意思
Nervous? What's that mean?
我也不清楚
I'm not sure.
没人肯告诉我  我猜他们打算...
No one would tell me, but I think they're...
丢卒保车  以保护贾瓦迪
they're cutting their losses to protect Javadi.
丢卒保车
Cutting their losses?
我说过了  还不确定
I said I'm not sure.
是指我吗
Meaning me?
那是他
That's him.
他似乎在打电话
Looks like he's on the phone.
摩萨德的人在哪
Where's Mossad?
拜托  和我一起  坐上车就好
Please, just come with me, just get in the car.
去哪
And go where?
哪都行  求你了
Anywhere. Please.
求你  现在就跟我走
Please, just come with me now.
一旦出了德黑兰  我们就能重整旗鼓
As soon as we're clear of Tehran, we can regroup.
还重整旗鼓个屁
Regroup for what?
再做个操蛋的计划吗
What? To make another fucked-up plan?
不是  我们得离开
No, we just need to leave.
别这么说  行吗
Will you stop saying that?
离开  离开  去哪啊
Leave, leave. Leave where?
我无处可去  卡莉
I have nowhere to go, Carrie!
我不可能回美国了
I can't go back to the States.
那我们去别的地方
We'll go somewhere else.
做什么呢
And do what?
四处躲藏吗
Hide out?
然后他们追捕我们俩吗
So they're hunting us both?
我有人脉
I have contacts.
我已经经历过一次了  卡莉
I've been through that already, Carrie.
不想再来一次了
I won't do it again.
我也不会让你承受一次的
And I won't do it to you.
双人组在那里
And there's the Tag Team.
布洛迪  求你了
Brody, please.
见鬼
Shit.
已经开始了
It's happening.
什么事
What?
你背后  从清真寺走过来的两个男人
Behind you, from the mosque, there's two men,
一个穿着深色衬衫和卡其色裤子
one in a dark shirt and khaki pants,
另一个穿着皮夹克
the other in leather jacket.
别挂电话
Just stay on the phone
我会告诉你情况
and I will talk you through.
他在移动
He's moving.
-布洛迪  -快离开这里
- Brody? - Just get out of here.
有人提醒了他
Someone warned him.
谁干的
Who?
她真是狗胆包天
She wouldn't fucking dare.
怎么的
What?
你这事干得真操蛋
You really fucked up this time.
他是为我们工作的
He's working for us.
那个计划失败了
The plan failed.
所以你就派来人来杀他
So you send a hit squad?
我们试图把他召回  被他拒绝了
We tried to recall him. He said no.
现在托你的福  他可以在德黑兰
Now thanks to you, he's loose
街上自由行动  天知道他会干什么
on the streets of Tehran doing God knows what.
日安
Salaam.
日安  日安
Salaam, salaam.
[阿拉伯语]
拜托  告诉她
Please, tell her.
马上告诉她  这非常重要
Tell her right now. It's very important.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas?
我没想到你会来
I wasn't expecting you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
纳塞林  我需要你的帮助
Nassrin, I need your help.
发生什么事了
What happened?
你还好吗
Are you all right?
有人想杀我
Somebody just tried to kill me.
我的天
My God.
我得和达尼什·阿克巴里谈谈
I need to talk to Danesh Akbari.
达尼什
Danesh...
他可不喜欢被人打扰
he is a very private man.
我有...
I have...
我有关于马吉德·贾瓦迪的消息
I have information about Majid Javadi
绝对是他需要知道的
that he absolutely needs to know, okay?
这非常重要
It's very important.
求你了  纳塞林  求你
Please, Nassrin, please, okay?
好吧  好吧  我会告诉他的
All right, all right, I'll tell him.
我们从贾瓦迪那里收到一条消息
We got a message from Javadi.
布洛迪刚刚在革命卫队总部现身了
Brody just showed up at the Revolutionary Guard headquarters.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
贾瓦迪说护送他的人是阿克巴里的手下
Javadi said he was escorted by Akbari's men.
他要去见阿克巴里
He's going to Akbari.
布洛迪知道我们想杀他
Brody knows we just tried to kill him.
他会让整个计划全他妈泡汤
He's gonna burn the whole fucking thing down.
纳塞林告诉我你很激动
Nassrin told me you were upset.
想找我谈谈
That you wanted to talk to me.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你知道吗  我就是在这间办公室
You know, it was here in this office
第一次听说你的名字
that I first heard your name.
阿布·纳齐尔跟我谈起过你
Abu Nazir told me about you:
他找到了怎样的一块宝石
what a jewel he had found...
怎样的一把真主之剑
what a sword for Allah.
怎么会有人...
Why would anyone...
想要杀掉这样一件珍宝
want to kill such a treasure?
是想阻止我告诉你关于贾瓦迪的事情
To stop me telling you about Javadi.
贾瓦迪的什么事
What about Javadi?
他觊觎你的职位
He wants your job.
你以为我会不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
中情局已经为他计划好了
The CIA has planned it for him.
中情局
The CIA?
就算是贾瓦迪这样的人也不会和中情局合作的
Even Javadi wouldn't work with the CIA.
可他合作了
Well, he is.
他们发现他挪用了革命卫队几百万的公款
They found out he embezzled millions from the IRGC.
他们握住了他的把柄
They own him.
你是在逃犯
You were on the run.
你怎么会知道美国方面在做些什么
How could you know what the Americans are doing?
因为这个计划我也有份
Because I was part of it.
我来到德黑兰是为了接近你
I was to come here to Tehran to get close to you.
你接近我以后要干什么
And when you got close?
他们想让我把你除掉...
They wanted me to take you out...
以便让贾瓦迪取代你
...so they could replace you with Javadi.
那就是我接到的指令
Those were my orders.
不过你并不想执行这些指令
But you don't want to obey those orders.
所以你才会来找我
That's why you came to me.
我来这里是为了自我救赎
I came here to redeem myself.
你已经做到了
And you have.
已经做到了
You have.
谢谢你  尼古拉斯
Thank you, Nicholas.
我会对付贾瓦迪的
I will deal with Javadi.
你和阿布·纳齐尔谈起过我吗
You spoke with Abu Nazir about me?
就在这个房间吗
In this room?
是的
Yes.
谈起他是如何派你去对抗美国的
How he would send you against America.
就像一把插入敌人心脏的利剑
A sword to strike the heart of our enemy.
很好
Good.
都是在这里开始的
It all started here.
喂
Yes?
是我
It's me.
我在阿克巴里的办公室
I'm in Akbari's office.
布洛迪  你做了什么
Brody, what have you done?
我把他杀了
I killed him.
把我弄出去
Get me out of here.